

PERSONAL

- Name
 Arden Latraca
- ★ Address Sitio Kasagingan, Banawa, Brgy. Guadalupe, Cebu City 6000 Cebu City
- **Phone number** 09171888863
- Email denzanitized93@gmail.com
- Date of birth 27-10-1993
- Place of birth
 Pasig City
- Website http://www.denzanitized.com/
- **こ LinkedIn** https://www.linkedin.com/in/denzi

ARDEN LATRACA

A Senior software developer and Technical lead in my current project. I do have a strong background in Javascript specially in Knockout and Vue as well as JSP in frontend development since the project I am in right now is currently developing the frontend side of the system. However, I still do a bit of backend side such as Java Spring MVC, JSP, JSTL with JBoss as the local server.

I do have 8 years of experience in web development industry since all of my projects are web applications. I have big ambitions in life such as learn a lot of languages as long as I am still in the industry before retirement period. I want to have long term goal and relation with the company that has also has a wide vision for the future.



SKILLS

Vue JS	****
Knockout JS	****
JQuery	****
JSP	****
CSS/SASS	****
Java Spring	****
HTML	****
Javascript	****
Typescript	****
Webpack	****



WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

SENIOR TECHNICAL DEVELOPER TECH LEAD II

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the project
- Perform coding reviews
- Teach the team about the existing project standards and how to implement it during development
- Organize overall development phase

2018 - 2021

SENIOR TECHNICAL DEVELOPER TECH LEAD

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the project
- Perform coding reviews
- Teach the team about the existing project standards and how to implement it during development
- Organize overall development phase

2017 - 2018

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER II

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Develop applications based from the given client requirements
- Maintain coding standards for readable and maintainable codes
- Ensures the application with quality performance
- Create (HLD and LLD) based from requirements given
- Performs UT and multi-browser testing to maintain application quality
- Deliver the application based from the given client's schedule
- Analyze the best possible way on how to implement things during the

development process

Can work with less supervision
Technical in terms of development

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER
Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

Adapts easily with new environment

- Develop applications given the client's schedule
- Creates unit test cases and perform unit testing when necessary
- Maintains readable codes base on the company coding standards
- Follows internal schedule as much as possible
- Review codes thoroughly
- Learn basics from superiors

2014 - 2016 ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL DEVELOPER

Alliance Software Inc., Cebu

- Develop application for company use
- Design appropriate database design for the system
- Adjust easily with specification changes
- Perform thorough application testing
- Add new features if necessary
- Perform application demo with manager

2012 DATA ENCODER

University of Cebu, Cebu

- Encodes student enrollment form
- Print study load when successfully enrolled
- Drops subject enrolled if requested by student
- Changes subject schedule when requested



2015 - Present

C.. PROJECT

Web Application - Mail System (Secured Project)

>>> Language used:

- Vue JS
- Knockout JS
- JQuery
- Typescript
- ESLint
- Java Spring
- JSP
- XML
- CSS/SASS

Webpack (Bundler)

>>> Job Description:

- Lead in the development and implementation of the project
- Perform coding reviews
- Teach the team about the existing project standards and how to implement it during development
- Organize overall development phase
- Develop applications based from the given client requirements
- Maintain coding standards for readable and maintainable codes
- Ensures the application with quality performance
- Create (HLD and LLD) based from requirements given
- Performs UT and multi-browser testing to maintain application quality
- Deliver the application based from the given client's schedule
- Analyze the best possible way on how to implement things during the development process

• Can work with less supervision • Technical in terms of development M.. PROJECT 2015 **Web Application** >>> Language used: JUnit >>> Job Description: • Performs automated testing using JUnit 2014 - 2015

M.. PROJECT

Web Application (Centralized System)

>>> Language used:

- HTML
- CSS
- Java Spring
- Hibernate
- MySQL
- JQuery
- Javascript

>>> Job Description:

- Implement and develop assigned modules.
- Translate HLD and LLD to codes.
- Perform API calls.
- Fullstack developer

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY 2010 - 2014 University of Cebu, Cebu >>> Consecutive Top Student >>> Dean's Lister >>> Graduated with honor - "3rd honor with excellence award" **HIGHSCHOOL** 2006 - 2010 University of Cebu, Cebu >>> Consecutive Top Student 2000 - 2006 **Elementary**

Guadalupe Elementary School, Cebu



>>> JLPT N4 Passer (Issued Jan 2020 · No Expiration Date)

>>> Oracle Java OCA Passer (Issued Jul 2016 · No Expiration Date)